<Document>
  # Asakim

  Asakim are abandoned pre-fracture genetically enhanced reptillian bioweapons, they are remnants of long-gone wars, only woken up after extreme circumstances causing them to have a [color=red]cryostasis failure[/color] near the Colossus Sector.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobAsakim"/>
  </Box>

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingOuterHardsuitAsakim"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WeaponRifleAsakimAutopulser"/>
  </Box>

  ##As an Asakim:
  - You generally have no knowledge (maybe basic at most) of the sector and its inhabitants. You don't speak Andromeda standard, you shouldn't know about the culture of the TSF or USSP.
  - Your goal is to follow your orginal mission of securing a major point of interest and destroy or secure any [italic][color=#00CCFF]pre-fracture data[/color][/italic] you find.
  - [bold]Your gear is incredibly [color=#00CCFF]valued and rare[/color], you should never give it up for anything, it is your only posession.[/bold]
  - [color=green]Civilians and the innocent are not your enemy[/color], and can be bartered with (if you can get past the language barrier).

  [color=#00FFCC][bold][italic]Fight with honor, prevent harm to the innocent, and destroy anything that stands in your path.[/italic][/bold][/color]

  ##Species Notes:
  [bold]As a genemodded trained bioweapon, you'll find that:[/bold]
  - Your 2 additional small arms give you additional powerful melee damage, and inject 1u of [color=orange]Gastrotoxin[/color] on hit.
  - Your thick scales protect you more than they normally would.
  - Your additional eyes grants you basic biological nightvision.
  - You are generally bulkier than most, and have more power to drag things around.

  ## Misc Notes:
  - Asakim are generally undiscovered to the rest of the sector, and should be taken into mind IC.
  - [color=red][bold]Like Chimeras, you are not immune to safezone rules as an Asakim.[/bold][/color]
  - Asakim do not require escalation to fire at or be fired from.
  - You are allowed to work with ADS, and are allowed to know of their existence as they are Pre-Fracture tech.

</Document>
